# fernanda mora

B.Sc. Applied Mathematics 

■ B.Sc. Actuarial Sciences 

■ M.Sc. Computer Science



**about**Mexico city
June, 1987
+5215528862399

fernandamoralba@gmail

fernanda-mora.com

github.com/Sophie-Germain

### languages

spanish (native) english (high proficiency)

#### programming

R, Python, Matlab (fair) Java, C, C++ Bash (basic)

#### other

PostgreSQL, LaTeX, Sublime, Office Suite, GitHub, Docker

#### about

"If you cannot measure it, you cannot improve it". My major goal is to **generate value** through *state-of-the-art technologies and models* that tackle relevant problems in *society, government and companies*. My second goal is to promote a quantitative & data-driven approach to problem-solving and decision-making.

To achieve this I have developed a **unique academic & industry experience** that combines **theory + research** with a **practical + client-oriented approach**. Please take a look to my **website** to find a more detailed picture of my profile.

#### **Academic interests**

2017

- Computer Science: computer architecture, distributed computing
- Data Science and Machine Learning:
   Big Data, Deep Learning, Statistics

**BBVA Bancomer - Datio Analytics** 

• Finance: Derivatives, Risk Theory

#### Non-academic interests

- Strategic and Management Consulting
- · Value proposition and pricing
- BI analytics with data-driven solutions

Senior Data Scientist

# industry experience

	Working in Bancomer's 2nd generation Big Data platform (Dathe Analytics team in Mexico under the Scrum methodology.	atio). Leading
since 2015	Freelance consulting (Mexican Secretary of Energy, AbbV Business strategy, data mining and statistical consulting	<b>(ie)</b> Consultant
2015, 2m	<b>AbbVie Mexico</b> <i>Tailor-made value propositions for AbbVie's drug portfolio</i>	roject Coordinator
2013-2014	<b>LifeSciences Consultants</b> <i>Health economics, cost-effectiveness analysis, market access</i>	gement Consultant strategies
2010-2011	Sociedad Financiera Campesina Evaluation and assessment of credit portfolios	Financial Analyst
2012, 3m	ADRISA Estimation and forecasting of the premium of life insurances	Actuarial Analyst
2009-2010	Cuasar Capital S.C. Financial assessment of infrastructure and real-state projects	Financial Analyst

### education

since 2015	M.Sc. candidate in Computer Science Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de Mexico Working on machine learning models for automatic reading comprehension
2015	<b>B.Sc. in Applied Mathematics</b> Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de Mexico Thesis with special mention: Deep Learning Fundamentals Applied to Electric
	Energy Consumption Forecasting in Mexico. Link to thesis Link to deck
2012	B.Sc. in Actuarial Sciences Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de Mexico
	Thesis with special mention. Link to thesis

# academic experience

2016, 2m	Worked with Profr. Eric Nyberg in Machine Learning models for Q&A at the Language Technologies Institute.	
2016	Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de Mexico Graduate Seminar Professor Teaching Data Mining tools to support decision making. Github repo	
2015, 6m	Computational Research and Analysis Laboratory (ITAM)  Data Scientist  Machine learning and visualization of credit data for nonpayment prediction	
2010, 6m	Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de Mexico  Economics IV (non-competitive markets)  Teaching Assistant	

# **publications**

Local layered algorithmic model for topological design of rural telecommunications networks. Presented on the International Conference on Operations Research for Development, ICORD 2016. Link to paper

Carga Económica de la Diabetes Mellitus en México, 2013. Fundación Mexicana para la Salud A.C. Link to paper

### conferences

Dataday Mexico 2017: Speaker with a talk on Deep Learning.

**International Conference on Operations Research for Development, ICORD 2016**: Presenter of a paper and revisor of two papers.

# acknowledgments

- 90% Bachelor's tuition scholarship for strong academic performance
- 60% Master's tuition scholarship for strong academic performance
- National Council of Science and Technology Master's scholarship for strong academic performance